# EMILY SAHLANI

## DOCUMENTATION SPECIALIST



647.707.3675

Toronto, ON

https://www.emilysahlani.com/

linkedin.com/in/emily-rushton/

emilyrushton.github.io

## **TECHNOLOGIES**

Git & CI/CD

Next.js & React

HTML & CSS

REST & GraphQL APIs

Markdown & MDX

Javascript

Docusaurus

Jekyll, Liquid, YAML

**DITAXML** 

Algolia

Camtasia

## **EDUCATION**

#### MASTER OF SCIENCE

Technical Communication Northeastern University College of Professional Studies Sep 2015-Dec 2017

## **BACHELOR OF ARTS**

Honors English Language and Literature

## SUMMARY

Skilled technical leader with 9 years of experience in the software industry, specializing in technical communication and online help systems. Proficient in front-end tools and Git workflows, with a strong focus on creating user-friendly documentation. Quick to learn new products, ensuring thorough and comprehensive documentation. Highly inquisitive, always ready to explore and master software for effective documentation.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## MANAGER, DOCUMENTATION

Nov 2022-Present

Nautical Commerce, Toronto

- Enable developers and end-users to optimize our product through detailed API-references, tutorials, videos, release notes, and technical support.
- Empower internal teams and solution integration partners with interactive product training.
- Facilitate customer engagement with personalized product onboarding, including live training sessions and webinars.
- Develop and maintain a comprehensive documentation website utilizing Docusaurus, ensuring continuous access to up-to-date resources.

## MANAGER, PRODUCT OPERATIONS

Mar 2022-Nov 2022

Veeva Systems, Toronto

- Led all release & end-user documentation for a team of four in a highly-regulated industry.
- Facilitated monthly release preview webinars.
- Managed the product team's project milestones & deliverables throughout
- software development lifecycle.
- Facilitated release planning & design collaboration cycles between product
- management and engineering
- Managed an online help system serving 2,000 monthly users and delivered weekly customer release notifications.

## **TECHNICAL WRITER LEAD**

Apr 2020-Mar 2022

Veeva Systems, Toronto

- Expanded the technical writing team and managed all release publishing activities.
- Regularly produce content to support how to enable and use new features being released on a monthly-basis.
- Onboarded and trained technical writers on software and authoring tools.
- Implemented a GitLab CI/CD pipeline for automated online help updates.
- Developed processes and style guides to support the growing team.

## EMILY LESLEY RUSHTON

University of Waterloo Sep 2010-Apr 2014

#### ACHIEVEMENTS

Employee Excellence Award - Bronze

Dell EMC Mar 2018

Employee Excellence Award - Gold

Dell EMC Jan 2017

## VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

**LEAD MOVER** 

Shelter Movers Nov 2020-Present

## **TECHNICAL WRITER**

Mar 2019-Apr 2020

Veeva Systems, Toronto

- Built out a new documentation set for the launch of a cloud-based drug safety product, Vault Safety, including user guides and release notes.
- Built an online help website using Jekyll, GitLab, and AWS hosting.

## TECHNICAL CONTENT DEVELOPER II

Sep 2017-Mar 2019

Dell EMC, Burlington

- Delivered targeted IT administration documentation for multiple backup and recovery products, balancing concurrent release schedules.
- Resolved peers' technical DITA XML issues, conducting standards reviews for the team.
- Performed code reviews for the engineering team to improve user interface verbiage quality.

## TECHNICAL CONTENT DEVELOPER I

Jul 2015-Sep 2017

Dell EMC, Burlington

- Collaborated with engineering teams to produce quality end-user documentation on NetWorker, backup and recovery software.
- Developed SEO best practices to enhance document searchability.

## PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

## MANAGING PEOPLE: ESSENTIALS Oct 2021

University of Toronto School of Continuing Studies

CRAFTING MEMORABLE AND INFLUENTIAL PRESENTATIONS Nov 2020

Society for Technical Communication

## ADVANCED TECHNICAL EDITING Sep 2019

Society for Technical Communication